JAKE MILLER

Pasadena, CA 91106 (relocating to Denver end of April)

jake-miller@hotmail.com, (651) 356-4981, https://jmiller-io.github.io/

SUMMARY

Engineering solutions for technical challenges since 2009. I discovered my love for software development during my time as an IT Systems Engineer, when it became clear that the more architectural aspects of technology were the strengths I wanted to develop the most. Taking ideas and turning them into functional, elegant applications is my mission.

EXPERIENCE

Technical Engineer | Windows Operations, CBS, Hollywood 7/2016 – 10/2016

- Assists vendors and internal departments with Windows server hosted service migrations and upgrades
- Ensures security policy compliance for the Windows environment by performing Operating System patching and application modernizations
- Maintains infrastructure equipment inventory and manages hardware life-cycle
- Performs data center management, including cable organization and hardware installation
- Provides troubleshooting and advanced analysis of requests within the Windows 2000 2012
 R2 environment

Windows Systems Administrator, American Public Media Group, LA, 1/2013 – 9/2016

- Architects and manages the Active Directory environment for a multi-site hierarchy
- Assists in the architectural development and deployment of new installations and solutions in an ever-expanding VMware environment within a continuous improvement organization
- Automates administrative tasks in AD, Office 365, Exchange Online and VMware with the use of PowerShell and PowerCLI
- Designs and implements software deployments, updates, OSD and systems management solutions with the use of SCCM
- Develops, installs, recommends purchases, implementations and configuration of Microsoft technologies and Infrastructure systems
- Oversees the administration and operation of the physical server, telephony, networking and storage infrastructure, in data centers and offices geographically located around the country
- Researches, evaluates and recommends new technologies to meet business requirements and contributes to long-range planning for systems evolution
- Supports, upgrades and maintains media and broadcast related Microsoft servers and applications that are critical to the operation of the American Public Media Group automation and play to air systems in a 24x7x365 environment

SIS Systems Administrator I, Infinite Campus, Inc., Blaine, MN, 7/2012 – 12/2012

- Assists with the testing and deployment of internal operations tools; contributes to increased customer service and efficient product delivery
- Configures and installs a customer-purchased web application, and dependent software, to remote-access servers and maintains the internal system requirements for continued software delivery and use at the largest American-owned Student Information System provider
- Executes timely XML code changes and Apache Tomcat upgrades to ensure continued functionality of the web application during a continuous product development cycle
- Performs SQL server database management, including any necessary script modification and execution
- Manages client database backup tasks through use of an internally-built tool; processes requested database restores and ensures the availability of client data

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript

iQuery/AJAX

MongoDB

Express.js

AngularJS

Node.js

HTML

CSS

RESTful APIs

Git/GitHub

AWS Storage (S3, Glacier)

Template Engines

PostgreSQL

Ruby on Rails

PowerShell

Application Virtualization

VEEAM

VMware

Windows Server 2000-2012 R2

Azure AD

EDUCATION

Web Development Immersive, General Assembly, LA, 3/2017	
Associate of Applied Science, Computer Networking , Dunwoody College of Technology, Minneapolis, MN, 12/2010	